MANIMARAN SELVAN

LEADER / MANAGER / ARCHITECT (Belgium Work Permit – D Visa)

mselvan@belyf.com | +32 494 80 63 77 | https://blog.belyf.com/ | https://linkedin.com/in/maniselvan/



SUMMARY

A software engineer at heart, with 15 years in the field and 6 years in technical product management, I've led initiatives that have significantly boosted efficiency and growth. Known for high-impact strategic decision-making and collaborative leadership, I excel in nurturing high-performing teams and processes.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Co-founded 2 startups (FinTech & EComm).
- Contributed to <u>CloudFix</u> development, yielding \$15M+ internal and \$100M+ customer savings.
- Increased throughput 5x via SLA-driven lean assembly lines.
- Led IT consolidation, saving \$4.3M/year.
- Led post-acquisition of Jive (\$462M), reducing the TCO by 90%.
- Modernized legacy software, reducing millions of LOC to 5K.
- Architected 10+ software platforms from scratch, delivering on time within budget.
- Achieved top 1% in CCAT, demonstrating exceptional cognitive skills.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Strategic Planning, Leadership & Team Collaboration, Agile & Lean Methodologies, Continuous Improvement, Product Vision & Mission, Vendor Management, Stakeholder Management, Change Management, Software Engineering, Decision Making, Coaching/Mentoring, People Management, Cross-functional Collaboration, Conflict Resolution, Emerging Technologies

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Java, Groovy, Javascript, Python, AWS, GCP, API Gateway, AppSync, Lambda, EventBridge, Step Functions, Gradle, Maven, Jenkins, UAT Testing, Alpha/Beta Testing, A/B Testing, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Neptune, Redis, Athena, Docker, K8s, REST, GraphQL, Git, SVN, CVS, Figma, Balsamiq, SNS, Kinesis, Kafka, Lucidchart, Draw.io, Quicksight, Grafana

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Enterprises, Inc.

Austin, Texas (Remote)

Technical Product Manager, Central TPM founding member.

- Aug 2017 Jun 2023
- Led initiatives saving \$15M+, Productized strategies resulting in \$100M+ savings.
- Implemented assembly lines, enabling 24/7 operations for a 5K+ global workforce.
- Co-managed 60+ TPMs with retiring VP, preparing for VP role.
- Developed tools for spec ordering, search, stack ranking, and CTO bootcamps.

Lead Software Engineer, Acting IT Ops Manager.

Jan 2015 - Aug 2017

- Centralized IT Ops for 5K+ global workforce, achieving 85% cost savings.
- Coached and managed 20+ senior SREs, making them deliver 4x value.
- Authored M&A IT transition playbooks, resulting in integrating 15+ acquisitions.
- Set up JIRA workflows and automation, creating an enterprise-wide unified process.

Tissow Technology Ventures, LLP.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Oct 2013 - Dec 2015

- Conceived, developed, and delivered Humingo, an e-commerce product aggregation platform, in 6 months.
- Modernized Ticketgoose, a bus ticket booking and operator management platform, in 3 months with new tech and simplified architecture.
- Optimized tech operations, reducing TCO by 50%.

Nallan Technology Ventures Private Limited.

Chennai, India

Senior Associate, Technical Lead.

Dec 2011 - Oct 2013

 Steered the architecture and deployment of Kachyng, a PCI-compliant mobile payments platform with single-click checkout and ads.

EMRG Software Solutions Private Limited.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Aug 2010 - Nov 2011

(Originally from Aug 2009)

 Hired and managed a 10-member software engineering and SaaS team, developing two software products in the financial information research space.

YuMe India Private Limited.

Chennai, India

Systems Engineer, IT Operations founding member.

Jan 2010 - Aug 2010

 Managed infrastructure and automated deployments across 6 internal environments; oversaw bi-weekly production deployments, weekly migrations, & daily DevOps tasks.

Java Application Developer.

Aug 2008 – Jan 2010

(Originally Concord IT – Acquired by YuMe)

 Pioneered R&D in early mobile technologies and delivered native apps; created proofof-concepts in Google Web Toolkit.

EDUCATION

B.Sc Computer Science, Bharathidasan University, Trichy, India.

2008